Guide to the Miriam Schlein Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Miriam Schlein papers
1949-2007
GEN MSS 621
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
38
(40 boxes) + 3 record album storage
The collection consists primarily of writings, including drafts and manuscripts, and research material, as well as correspondence, clippings, printed material, photographs, slides, phonographic records and other material. The collection documents Miriam Schlein's career as a children's author and her process of researching and writing books on natural history and related topics.
Schlein, Miriam
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Miriam Schlein Papers were purchased from Elizabeth S. Weiss and John Weiss on the Jockey Hollow Fund, 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Books from the Schlein collection are cataloged separately, with their provenance traced.
Miriam Schlein (1926-2004)
Miriam Schlein was born on 6 June 1926 in Brooklyn, NY. Schlein was a prolific author of children's books which focused on teaching young readers about animals, science, and other topics. She earned a B.A. in psychology from Brooklyn College in 1947 before moving into the fields of publishing and advertising.
While working for the publisher Simon & Schuster in the children's department, she was inspired to write her own books for children. Beginning with 1951's A Day at the Playground, she went on to write nearly one hundred books over five decades. Although she wrote a number of fiction stories, such as Oomi, the New Hunter (1955), The Snake in the Carpool (1963), and I Sailed with Columbus (1991), she concentrated on books which explored the natural sciences. Among her award-winning efforts in this genre are Fast Is Not a Ladybug: A Book about Fast and Slow Things (1953), Elephant Herd (1954), What's Wrong with Being a Skunk? (1974), Giraffe, the Silent Giant (1976), The Dangerous Life of the Sea Horse (1986), and Discovering Dinosaur Babies (1991).
Miriam Schlein married Harvey Weiss, an artist who illustrated some of her early works. Before her marriage with Weiss ended in divorce, the couple had two children.
Miriam Schlein died of vasculitis on 23 November 2004 in New York City.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists primarily of writings, including drafts and manuscripts, and research material, as well as correspondence, clippings, printed material, photographs, slides, phonographic records and other material. The collection documents Miriam Schlein's career as a children's author and her process of researching and writing books on natural history and related topics.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series: I. Writing Files, 1955-2002; II. Research Material, 1949-2003; III. Correspondence, 1954-2002; and IV. Personal Papers, 1976-2004.
Animals -- Juvenile fiction; Authors, American -- Juvenile literature; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Children's literature, American -- 20th Century; Children's stories, American; Illustrations (layout features); Photographs; Science -- Juvenile literature; Schlein, Miriam
- Writing Files, 1955-2002; Series I; 23.75
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists primarily of drafts, manuscripts, and notes for many of Schlein's published works as well as some of her uncompleted book projects. Also found is some research material and correspondence relating to Schlein's published works.
  Related Archival Materials note
  Related material can be found in Research Material and Correspondence.
  Arrangement
  Files are arranged in alphabetical order by book or project title.
  - 10 Days / Dead Dad (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "2002 Ideas", circa 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "20th Century Children's Books" (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adult Book Ideas (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Adventure", draft (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Adventures Of A Button", draft (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Almanac Project" (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Always Right Now" (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Amazing Mr. Pelgrew" (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Amuny, Boy Of Old Egypt", circa 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 10-22)
  - "Amuny, Boy Of Old Egypt", circa 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
  - "Animal Fighting", circa 1979 (Box 2, Folder 25-29)
    Includes material relating to the book, Snake Fights, Rabbit Fights, & More: A Book About Animal Fighting.
  - "Animal Haiku", drafts (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "Animal Navigation", typescript (Box 2, Folder 31-33)
  - Animal Photos (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "Animal Play" (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Animal Poems (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Animal Smarts", proposal (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
  - "Animal Shapes" (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "The Animal's World" (Box 2, Folder 40-45)
  - "Antarctica", circa 1978 (Box 3, Folder 46-57)
  - "Are We Dumber Than Arthur The Mutt?" (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - "Arrivals and Departures" (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Assorted Jewish Stories (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Assorted Short Stories (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - "August", screenplay (Box 3, Folder 62-66)
  - "August", screenplay (Box 4, Folder 67-68)
  - "The Battle Begins" (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - "Bear Cubs" (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - "Before The Dinosaurs" (Box 4, Folder 71-74)
  - "Beowolf" (Box 4, Folder 75-76)
  - "The Best Place" (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - "The Big Cheese" (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - "Big Lion, Little Lion", drafts (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - "Big Race", circa 1975-1984 (Box 4, Folder 80-82)
  - "Big Talk" (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - "Billy The Littlest One" (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - "Bird", drafts (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - "Bobo the Troublemaker" (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Book Proofs (Box 4, Folder 87-88)
  - Book Proposals (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - "Bozo Says OK" (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - "Brave Bertram" (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Bryce Canyon (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - The Cat That Sailed To France (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - "Catfish" (Box 5, Folder 94-95)
  - "CCI" (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - "Charlie Frye And The Nun", circa 1963 (Box 5, Folder 97-104)
  - "China" (Box 5, Folder 105-106)
  - "Christopher Columbus" (Box 5, Folder 107-113)
  - "Christopher Columbus" (Box 6, Folder 114-115)
  - "The City Mother" (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - "City Stuff" (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - "Cockeyed! / Henry's Hammer" (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - "Color Me Red White and Blue", drafts (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - "A Commonplace Miracle" (Box 6, Folder 120-121)
  - "Connecticut Marriage" (Box 6, Folder 122-123)
    Includes: Quality of Education, Dance for Mental Health, Super-Widow and Mr. Clean, and Visitation.
  - "Coral Reef", circa 2002 (Box 6, Folder 124-127)
    Includes material relating to Schlein's Fish City manuscript.
  - "Creatures Real and Unreal" (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - "Crouching Little White Rabbits" (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - "Cubs Grow", drafts (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - "Dance For Mental Health", drafts (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - "The Dangerous Life of the Sea Horse" (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - "Dark And Light" (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - "Darwin" (Box 6, Folder 134-137)
    Includes material relating to "Darwin and Evolution" and "The Animals' World".
  - "The Day Bertram Disappeared" (Box 6, Folder 138-139)
  - "A Day In New York" (Box 6, Folder 140-141)
  - "The Day The Queen Ate The Banana" (Box 6, Folder 142)
  - "The Day The Queen Ate The Banana" (Box 7, Folder 143-146)
  - "The Day The Wallabies Followed Me Home" (Box 7, Folder 147-148)
  - "The Day They Went To The Top" (Box 7, Folder 149-150)
  - "Days Of Hope And Glamour" (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - "Deer" (Box 7, Folder 152-153)
  - "Dino Quiz Book" (Box 7, Folder 154-155)
  - "Discovering Dinosaur Babies" (Box 7, Folder 156-158)
  - "Divine Archer (Moon Myth)" (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - "Does The World Need Whales?", draft (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - "The Dog, The Cat and The Pumpernickel" (Box 7, Folder 161)
  - "Dragon" (Box 7, Folder 162)
  - "Elephant Herd" (Box 7, Folder 163-164)
  - "Enough Is Enough" (Box 7, Folder 165)
  - Environmental Impact Statement (Box 7, Folder 166)
  - "Finding Faraway Places" (Box 7, Folder 167)
  - "Fish City" (Box 7, Folder 168-170)
  - "Fish City" (Box 8, Folder 171-172)
  - "The Fisherman's Day" (Box 8, Folder 173-174)
  - "Flame And The Mammoth", circa 1955 (Box 8, Folder 175-188)
  - "Flier, Camp Story" (Box 8, Folder 189)
  - "Frieda" (Box 8, Folder 190)
  - "Funny Fingers" (Box 8, Folder 191)
  - Galleys And Jacket Blurbs (Box 8, Folder 192)
  - "The Game", drafts (Box 8, Folder 193)
  - "Giraffe: The Silent Giant" (Box 8, Folder 194-195)
  - "The Girl Who Would Rather Climb Trees" (Box 8, Folder 196)
  - "Go With Sun" (Box 8, Folder 197)
  - "Goof-up Day" (Box 8, Folder 198)
  - "Grandma's Gone" (Box 8, Folder 199)
  - "Grandpa's Turnip And Other Russian Tales" (Box 8, Folder 200)
  - Hawaii Voyage (Box 8, Folder 201)
  - "He" (Box 8, Folder 202)
  - "Hello, Hello!", proofs (Box 9, Folder 203-205)
  - "Here Go!" (Box 9, Folder 206)
  - Hippo - Goodall Press (Box 9, Folder 207)
  - "Home, The Tale Of A Mouse" (Box 9, Folder 208-210)
  - "Houses" (Box 9, Folder 211-217)
  - "The House's Heart", draft (Box 9, Folder 218)
  - "How Gorillas Have Fun" (Box 9, Folder 219-220)
  - "How Is A Mouse Like A Hippo?" (Box 9, Folder 221-223)
  - "How To Write A Book", draft (Box 9, Folder 224)
  - "I Am An Island" (Box 9, Folder 225)
  - "I Hate It", draft (Box 9, Folder 226)
  - "I, Tut" (Box 9, Folder 227)
  - "I, Tut" (Box 10, Folder 228-233)
  - "I Want A Panda!" (Box 10, Folder 234-237)
  - "I Want To Catch A Panda!" (Box 10, Folder 238-240)
  - "If I Were A Bird" (Box 10, Folder 241)
  - "If You Were A Hungry Dinosaur" (Box 10, Folder 242-245)
  - "In The City The Children Play" (Box 10, Folder 246-249)
  - "An Insider's Holiday In New York" (Box 10, Folder 250)
  - "Into The Right Ear And Out The Left: Three Magic Tales", draft (Box 10, Folder 251)
  - "The Invisible Mouse" (Bertram) (Box 10, Folder 252)
  - "Is One Always Just One?" (Box 10, Folder 253)
  - "The Island Of Tiny Elephants" (Box 10, Folder 254)
  - "The Island Of Tiny Elephants" (Box 11, Folder 255-256)
  - "Jason's Lucky Day", drafts (Box 11, Folder 257)
  - "Juju-Sheep And The Python's Moonstone", proofs (Box 11, Folder 258-262)
  - "Kinkajou" (Box 11, Folder 263)
  - "Kolea Bird" (Box 11, Folder 264-265)
  - "Laurie Sings" (Box 11, Folder 266-267)
  - "Laurie's New Brother" (Box 11, Folder 268)
  - "Lazy Day" (Box 11, Folder 269)
  - "The Learning Book", drafts (Box 11, Folder 270)
  - "Lee Ling's Dragon", circa 1999 (Box 11, Folder 271-277)
  - "Lee Ling's Dragon" (Box 12, Folder 278-301)
  - "Leonardo's Fossils", drafts (Box 12, Folder 302)
  - "Let's Go Dinosaur Tracking" (Box 12, Folder 303-304)
  - "Let's Go, Ma!", circa 1997 (Box 12, Folder 305)
  - "Little Big Nose (Eskimo)" (Box 12, Folder 306)
  - "Little Dog Little" (Box 12, Folder 307)
  - "Little Dog Little" (Box 13, Folder 308-310)
  - "The Little Girl Who Knew All about Kittens" (Box 13, Folder 311-312)
  - "The Little Girl's Wishes" (Box 13, Folder 313)
  - "Little Goat" (Box 13, Folder 314)
  - "Little Mouse" (Box 13, Folder 315)
  - "Little Rabbit" (Box 13, Folder 316-317)
  - "Little Raccoon Wants To Fly" (Box 13, Folder 318)
  - "Little Raccoon's Question", proof (Box 13, Folder 319-320)
  - "Little Rednose" (Box 13, Folder 321)
  - "Little Seal" (Box 13, Folder 322)
  - "Littlest One" (Box 13, Folder 323)
    Also includes material relating to "The Green Kite".
  - "A Long Pause Before Dying" (Box 13, Folder 324)
  - "Look At Me Now!" (Box 13, Folder 325-326)
  - "Lost Brother (Pygmy)" (Box 13, Folder 327)
  - "Lovely In Their Innocence" (Box 13, Folder 328-330)
    Also includes material relating to "Crouching Little White Rabbits".
  - "Lucky Mama" (Box 13, Folder 331-333)
    Also includes material relating to "Fish City".
  - "Lucky Porcupine" (Box 13, Folder 334)
  - "Lucky Rhinos" (Box 13, Folder 335)
    Also includes material relating to "Animal Haiku" and other works.
  - "Ma Says Moo And All Kinds Of Babies" (Box 13, Folder 336)
  - "Magic Picture Frame" (Box 14, Folder 337)
  - "The Magic Transformation Of Jimmy Kosnowsky" (Box 14, Folder 338)
  - "Maisie's Secret" (Box 14, Folder 339)
  - "Mal Di Denti" (Box 14, Folder 340)
  - "The Man Who Discovered The Panda" (Box 14, Folder 341)
  - "Manatee" (Box 14, Folder 342)
  - "Marriage Essay" (Box 14, Folder 343)
  - "Mashed Potatoes and Gravy" (Box 14, Folder 344)
  - "Max's Adventure" (Box 14, Folder 345)
  - "Me And The Mammoth" (Box 14, Folder 346-347)
  - "Metric" (Box 14, Folder 348-351)
  - Miscellaneous from desk (Box 14, Folder 352)
  - Miscellaneous poems (Box 14, Folder 353)
  - Miscellaneous shorts and notes (Box 14, Folder 354)
  - Miscellaneous typescripts (Box 14, Folder 355)
  - Miscellaneous writings (Box 14, Folder 356)
  - "The Mitten Story", drafts (Box 14, Folder 357)
  - "Mr. Carmichael", drafts (Box 14, Folder 358)
  - "Mr. Clean", drafts (Box 14, Folder 359)
  - "Mister Mister What's The Hurry" (Box 14, Folder 360)
  - "Monster In The Lake (Box 14, Folder 361)
  - "Monster In The Lake" (Box 15, Folder 362-365)
  - "Moon Dog" (Box 15, Folder 366)
    Also includes material relating to "The House's Heart".
  - "Moon Month And Sun Days" (Box 15, Folder 367-369)
  - "Moon Myths" (Box 15, Folder 370-373)
  - "Moon Stories" (Box 15, Folder 374-375)
  - "Mother", drafts (Box 15, Folder 376)
  - "Mouse" (Box 15, Folder 377)
  - Murder mystery book (Box 15, Folder 378)
  - "My Family" (Box 15, Folder 379-381)
  - "My House", circa 1971 (Box 15, Folder 382-384)
  - "My Mommy Had Lots Of Jobs" (Box 15, Folder 385)
  - "Navigation" (Box 15, Folder 386)
  - "New York Holiday" (Box 15, Folder 387)
  - "The Night The Batman Screwed Up" (Box 15, Folder 388-389)
  - "The Night The Batman Screwed Up" (Box 16, Folder 390)
  - "A Night To Remember" (Box 16, Folder 391)
    Also includes material relating to "Hanukkah".
  - Non-circulating MSS (Box 16, Folder 392)
  - "Nose Like A Hose" (Box 16, Folder 393)
  - Odd snippets and starts (Box 16, Folder 394)
  - "An Old Lady" (Box 16, Folder 395)
  - Old roughs (Box 16, Folder 396)
  - Old stories and poems (Box 16, Folder 397)
  - "Oomi" (Box 16, Folder 398-403)
  - "Original MSS for Showtime" (Box 16, Folder 404)
  - Panda article, drafts (Box 16, Folder 405)
  - Panda-Bamboo connection, drafts (Box 16, Folder 406)
  - Panda galleys (Box 16, Folder 407-408)
  - "Pandas Galore" (Box 16, Folder 409-411)
  - Panda notes (Box 16, Folder 412)
  - Panda proofs (Box 16, Folder 413)
  - Panda scraps (Box 16, Folder 414)
  - "Panda Watch" (Box 16, Folder 415)
  - "Panda Watch" (Box 17, Folder 416-418)
  - Parent One Year award (Box 17, Folder 419)
  - Partial ideas (Box 17, Folder 420)
  - "Paul The Airplane Pilot" (Box 17, Folder 421)
  - "The Pearl", drafts (Box 17, Folder 422-423)
    Also includes material relating to "In The City The Children Play".
  - "Penguins" (Box 17, Folder 424-436)
  - "Phoney Paul Revere", drafts (Box 17, Folder 437)
  - "Phyllis Blandings" (Box 17, Folder 438)
  - "Platypus" (Box 17, Folder 439-440)
  - Poems (Box 17, Folder 441-442)
  - "The Poor Boy", drafts (Box 17, Folder 443)
  - "Princess Moonlight" (Box 17, Folder 444)
  - "Puerto Rico" (Box 17, Folder 445-446)
  - "Puerto Rico" (Box 18, Folder 447)
  - "The Puzzle Of The Dinosaur Bird" (Box 18, Folder 448-451)
  - "The Quality Of Education", drafts (Box 18, Folder 452)
  - "Rabbit World" (Box 18, Folder 453)
  - "Raggle Taggle" (Box 18, Folder 454-455)
  - "Real Taste vs. Fad Taste" (Box 18, Folder 456)
  - "A Room From The Past" (Box 18, Folder 457)
  - "Roses Are For Noses" (Box 18, Folder 458)
  - "Round As A Ball" (Box 18, Folder 459)
  - "Safari" (Box 18, Folder 460)
  - "San Diego Wild Animal Park" (Box 18, Folder 461)
  - "San Miguel", article and correspondence (Box 18, Folder 462)
  - "Scofield's Tree House" (Box 18, Folder 463)
  - "Seahorse" (Box 18, Folder 464)
  - "Seal And Bay" (Box 18, Folder 465)
  - "Secret Land Of The Past" (Box 18, Folder 466-473)
  - "Secret Land Of The Past" (Box 19, Folder 474)
  - "Send out", scripts (Box 19, Folder 475)
  - Short stories (Box 19, Folder 476)
  - "Sidney Marks" (Box 19, Folder 477-478)
  - "Six Little Puppies" (Box 19, Folder 479)
  - "The Sixth Year" (Box 19, Folder 480)
  - "Sleep Safe, Little Whale", promotional material (Box 19, Folder 481-482)
  - "The Sleeping Dog Dreams" (Box 19, Folder 483)
  - "The Snake In The Carpool" (Box 19, Folder 484-485)
  - "Something For Now, Something For Later" (Box 19, Folder 486)
  - "Squirrel" (Box 19, Folder 487-488)
  - Starts and ideas (Box 19, Folder 489)
  - "The Stolen Moon" (Box 19, Folder 490)
  - "The Story About Me" (Box 19, Folder 491-496)
  - "The Story Of Katherine And Laura" (Box 19, Folder 497)
  - Stories to hold (Box 19, Folder 498)
  - "Strange Doings At Harper's Shoe" (Box 19, Folder 499-502)
  - "Strange Prehistoric Elephants" (Box 19, Folder 503)
  - "The Street" (Box 19, Folder 504)
  - "A Study Of Life" (Box 19, Folder 505)
  - "The Sun, Sea, Wind And Rain" (Box 20, Folder 506)
  - "Teacher" (Box 20, Folder 507)
  - "Ten Little Billy Goats" (Box 20, Folder 508)
  - Text book drafts (Box 20, Folder 509)
  - "That's Not Goldie!" (Box 20, Folder 510)
  - "The Three Frog Sisters" (Box 20, Folder 511)
  - "Three Russian Tales" (Box 20, Folder 512-513)
  - "Three Almost Grown-Up Sisters" (Box 20, Folder 514)
  - "Through A Nameless Door" (Box 20, Folder 515)
  - "Tie A Ribbon Round The Birch Tree" (Box 20, Folder 516)
  - "Time Flies!", draft (Box 20, Folder 517)
  - "Time" (Box 20, Folder 518-519)
  - "To George, With Love" (Box 20, Folder 520-521)
  - "Toot Toot Tootsie, Goodbye" (Box 20, Folder 522)
  - "Traveling Light" (Box 20, Folder 523)
  - "The Turning Point" (Box 20, Folder 524)
  - TV ideas (Box 20, Folder 525)
  - TV scripts - Pilgrims (Box 20, Folder 526)
  - "Twins!", circa 1998 (Box 20, Folder 527-528)
  - "Two Years/What Have We Done?" (Box 20, Folder 529)
  - Unidentified writings (Box 20, Folder 530-531)
  - "U.S.S. Greeneville" (Box 20, Folder 532)
  - "The Used To Be Animal Book", draft (Box 20, Folder 533)
  - "Using Parts Of A Book" (Box 20, Folder 534)
  - Various story drafts (Box 20, Folder 535)
    Also includes some correspondence.
  - Various story drafts (Box 21, Folder 536-556)
  - Various story drafts (Box 22, Folder 557-558)
  - "The Victrola" (Box 22, Folder 559)
  - "Visitation - Rapunzel" (Box 22, Folder 560)
  - "Wait Till Sunday", circa 1956 (Box 22, Folder 561)
  - "Waiting For The Boat" (Box 22, Folder 562)
  - "Whale" (Box 22, Folder 563-571)
  - "What? Burn All Picassos" (Box 22, Folder 572)
  - "What Does It Mean / Say What?" (Box 22, Folder 573)
  - "What Did You Do, Grandma?" (Box 22, Folder 574)
  - "What is Dark" (Box 22, Folder 575)
  - "What Happened To The Elephant?" (Box 22, Folder 576-577)
  - "What Is A Whale Not?" (Box 22, Folder 578)
  - "What Is Your Bumper-Sticker Profile?" (Box 22, Folder 579)
    Also includes material relating to "The Pride Of The City Fathers".
  - "What Makes A Dinosaur A Dinosaur?" (Box 22, Folder 580)
  - "What Makes A Dinosaur A Dinosaur?" (Box 23, Folder 581)
  - "What The Dinosaur Saw" (Box 23, Folder 582)
  - "What The Elephant Was" (Box 23, Folder 583-591)
  - "What Will You Be Like?" (Box 23, Folder 592)
  - "Where Are You Going, Marco?" (Box 23, Folder 593)
  - "Where Is Elizabeth?" (Box 23, Folder 594-596)
  - "Who Understands The Nature Of Death?" (Box 23, Folder 597)
  - "The Wife Who Lost Her Shadow", draft (Box 23, Folder 598)
  - "Wingsong" (Box 23, Folder 599-600)
  - "A Woman" (Box 23, Folder 601)
  - "A Woman" (Box 24, Folder 602)
  - "A Woman Looks At Divorce" (Box 24, Folder 603-610)
  - "The Wonder Of Things" (Box 24, Folder 611)
  - "Words, Wonderful Words" (Box 24, Folder 612)
  - "Worth another look" manuscripts (Box 24, Folder 613-614)
  - Writing quotes? / Interview material (Box 24, Folder 615)
  - "The Year Of The Panda" (Box 24, Folder 616-617)
  - "The Zappala Twins Take A Dive" (Box 24, Folder 618-619)
  - "Zebra World" (Box 24, Folder 620)
  - "Zoe's Book Of Manners" (Box 24, Folder 621)
- Research Material, 1949-2003; Series II; 7.5
  This series consists of material created and accumulated by Schlein in the course of researching topics for her books, and planning and carrying out various book projects. Material includes mostly clippings, notes, and book proposals, as well as some writings and correspondence.
  Related material can be found in Writing Files and Correspondence.
  Files are arranged in alphabetical order by topic or title.
  - Animal Communication (Box 24, Folder 622)
  - Animal Emergencies (Box 24, Folder 623)
  - Animal Eyes (Box 24, Folder 624)
  - Animal Fighting (Box 24, Folder 625)
  - Animal Navigation (Box 25, Folder 626)
  - Animal notes (Box 25, Folder 627)
  - Animal Quiz (Box 25, Folder 628)
  - Animal Smarts (Box 25, Folder 629)
  - Antartica (Box 25, Folder 630-633)
  - "Appropriate Names" (Box 25, Folder 634)
  - Art samples (Box 25, Folder 635)
  - Baby names and Baby Animals (Box 25, Folder 636)
  - Bat Research (Box 25, Folder 637)
  - "Before The Dinosaurs" (Box 25, Folder 638-640)
  - "Bestiary" (Box 25, Folder 641)
  - Bits That Grow Big: The Story Of Plant Reproduction by Irma E. Webber, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 642)
  - Bolivia notes (Box 25, Folder 643)
    Includes notes for "Secret Land Of The Past".
  - "Boy of Pompeii" (Box 25, Folder 644-645)
  - Cavemen research, notebook (Box 25, Folder 646)
  - Child Development (Box 25, Folder 647)
  - "Christopher Columbus" (Box 25, Folder 648-649)
  - Clippings (Box 25, Folder 650-652)
    Includes clippings associated with op-ed pieces, "Go With The Sun", "Something For Now, Something For Later", and other works by Miriam Schlein.
  - Coelacanthus (Box 25, Folder 653)
  - "Coral Reef" (Box 25, Folder 654-655)
  - "Darwin" (Box 26, Folder 656-657)
  - "The Day The Ladies Voted" (Box 26, Folder 658)
  - Department Store careers (Box 26, Folder 659)
  - "Dining With Dinosaurs" (Box 26, Folder 660-661)
  - "Dino Quiz Book" (Box 26, Folder 662-663)
  - Dinosaurs (Box 26, Folder 664-666)
  - Dinosaur book ideas (Box 26, Folder 667)
  - Dinosaur Graveyard (Box 26, Folder 668-669)
  - Dinosaur notes (Box 26, Folder 670-673)
  - Dinosaur proposals (Box 26, Folder 674-676)
  - Dinosaur research (Box 26, Folder 677-680)
  - Dinosaurs! magazine and Bryce Canyon postcard (Box 26, Folder 681)
  - "Discovering Dinosaur Babies" (Box 26, Folder 682-684)
  - "Discovery Of The Amargasaurus" (Box 26, Folder 685)
  - Dragons index (Box 26, Folder 686)
  - "Earth Is A Jigsaw Puzzle" (Box 27, Folder 687)
  - Earthquake perdictions (Box 27, Folder 688)
  - Elephant notes (Box 27, Folder 689)
  - Elephant research (Box 27, Folder 690)
  - Elephant - photographic slides (Box 27, Folder 691)
  - "Elephants Of Long Ago" (Box 27, Folder 692)
  - Environment clippings (Box 27, Folder 693-694)
  - Environment series (Box 27, Folder 695)
  - "Evolution Of The Elephant", proposal (Box 27, Folder 696)
  - "Experts" (Box 27, Folder 697)
  - "Fad Taste" (Box 27, Folder 698)
  - "Film Woman - Incomplete" (Box 27, Folder 699)
  - Fish ideas (Box 27, Folder 700)
  - "From office shelf corner" (Box 27, Folder 701-703)
  - Gabler / Censorship, circa 1985 (Box 27, Folder 704-708)
  - Geology and Species info (Box 27, Folder 709)
  - "Ghost Ranch" (Box 27, Folder 710)
  - Giraffe research (Box 27, Folder 711-712)
  - Gorilla research (Box 27, Folder 713)
  - Green Turtle migration (Box 27, Folder 714)
  - Group names (Box 27, Folder 715)
  - "Halsey" (Box 28, Folder 716-717)
  - Hawaii (Box 28, Folder 718-719)
  - "HBU Text Papers" (Box 28, Folder 720)
  - "Helpful Handbook Of Facts And Systems", proposal (Box 28, Folder 721)
  - Hippopotamus (Box 28, Folder 722)
  - History of English language (Box 28, Folder 723)
  - "Hit And Run" (Box 28, Folder 724)
  - "How To Be A Good Writer" (Box 28, Folder 725)
  - "Hungry Dinosaurs" (Box 28, Folder 726)
  - "I, Tut" (Box 28, Folder 727-730)